

no Kareoja

Müllerstraße 130, 13349 Berlin, Germany

□ (+358) 050 3740592 | ■ tuomo.kareoja@gmail.com | □ TuomoKareoja | □ tuomo-kareoja

Summary and Skills

Data scientist/engineer specialized in relational databases, data pipelines and interactive dashboards. Domain knowledge in hospital management analysis and used cars market. Board games and piano for free time.

EU citizen

Programming Python, R, bash, LaTeX BI Tools Microsoft Power BI, Tableau Statistical Software RStudio, SPSS, SAS, RapidMiner Databases Posgresql, Microsoft SQL Server

DevOps Docker

Languages Finnish (native), English (fluent), German and Swedish (basic)

Finland

Helsinki, Finland

Experience _____

Data Scientist

NORDIC HEALTHCARE GROUP Feb. 2019 - Present

- Combining data all data pipelines to one with a new database (PostgreSQL, Python)
- · Champion for version control, project management tools, reproducibility and internal documentation (GitLab, Asana, ClickUp, Docker, Conda)

Data Analyst Finland

NORDIC HEALTHCARE GROUP Jan. 2017 - Feb. 2019

· Interactive visualization and discrete event simulations of hospital processes (Power BI, R, Python, PostgreSQL)

Junior Data Analyst Finland

GREY-HEN OY Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- · Quality control of the automated data gathering and report generation for models predicting prizes of used cars (SAS, R, Microsoft SQL Server)
- Documentation of the process chain and datasets

Teaching Assistant Finland

Jan. 2012 - Dec. 2016 University of Helsinki

• TA in numerous statistical courses at the departments of social psychology and statistics (SPSS, R)

Education

Data Science Bootcamp Berlin, Germany

Ивіоим July 2019 - December 2019

- On-site fulltime 5 month project based training course
- · Technologies used: Python, R, MySQL, Spark, AWS, Docker
- Algorithms used: GLM, KNN, RF, SVM, GBM, apriori, SARIMAX, Prophet...

B.S. in Statistics Helsinki, Finland

University of Helsinki 2012 - 2019

- Ongoing studies for a second major.
- Weighted grade average: 4.53 (scale 0-5)

M.Soc.Sc. in Social Psychology

UNIVERSITY OF HELSINKI 2012 - 2015

- Masters weighted grade average: 4.91 (scale 0-5), Master's thesis: Eximia
- Bachelor weighted grade average: 4.02 (scale 0-5)